# 佛山·顺德
Shunde, Foshan
# 阿姨 这个是什么
What are these, auntie?
# 这个是牛乳片
These are milk flakes
# 你们想要吃什么
Would you like something to eat?
# 看一下
Let me take a look
# 这边有双皮奶
Is there "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk")
# 有啊 双皮奶 姜撞奶 凤凰奶
Yeah. "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk"), "Jiang Zhuang Nai" ("ginger milk"), "Feng Huang Nai"
# 凤凰奶糊？
"Feng Huang Nai Hu"?
# 水牛奶
Water buffalo milk
# 这个叫牛乳片
These are milk flakes
# 就是牛奶放入醋里制作的
By adding vinegar into milk
# 牛奶加白醋会凝固
Milk coagulates with vinegar
# 这是什么东西啊
What are these?
# 那牛乳片怎么吃
How do we cook milk flakes?
# 牛乳片是回家吃 做 吃饭
Take them home, cook and have them with meal
# 吃饭？
With meal?
# 喉咙痛可以冲开水 这个清热散火
If you have a sore throat, have them in boiled water. It helps to relieve
# 哇 好神奇
Wow, amazing!
# 不是直接这么吃的是吧
We don't eat them directly, do we?
# 不是直接吃的
No, not directly
# 是回家做配饭的
Cook and have them with meals at home
# 牛乳片是咸的 除了冲水喝 还可煮粥
(Milk flakes are salty. Have them in water, or boil with congee)
# 比咸菜下饭  还可以做蒸蛋
(Works better than pickles. Can also be steamed with eggs)
# 我们要一个双皮奶吧
Let's have a "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk")
# 他们说 双皮奶是顺德比较特色的
We heard that "Shuang Pi Nai" is a specialty in Shunde
# 嗯 对
Hmm, yeah
# 不着急
No rush
# 我们正好路过看到这个东西 觉得很稀奇
We just passed by, and found it very interesting
# 这是我们家自产自销
We sell our homemade stuff
# 水牛奶都是自己的
Even the water buffalo milk is our own
# 水牛奶含脂量高达8%
(Water buffalo milk contains 8% fat)
# 他们说 顺德这边用的牛奶都是水牛奶
We heard that, all the milk in Shunde is water buffalo milk
# 对 对 对 是水牛奶
Yeah, yeah, right, water buffalo milk
# 这个模具
This is the mold
# 上面还有字
There's text on it
# 有
Right
# 金榜（街）牛乳片
Jinbang (street) milk flakes
# 阿姨 这里面放的是盐水吗
Auntie, is this salt water in the bowl?
# 就是因为盐水 我觉得才能够浮起来
I guess it has to be salt water, so that (the flakes) can float
# 对
Yes
# 盐水浸泡
Soak in salt water
# 否则的话 牛乳片这样的密度放进去
Otherwise, with such desity (of a milk flake)
# 肯定是沉下去的
It will sink for sure
# 一个姜撞奶 一个双皮奶 好不好
A "Jiang Zhuang Nai" ("ginger milk") and a "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk"), right?
# 可以
Yes
# 姜撞奶
Jiang Zhuang Nai
# 姜撞奶是现做的
The "Jiang Zhuang Nai" is freshly made
# 白砂糖
Sugar
# 现擦姜蓉
Fresh ginger mince
# 现做的东西 才真的好吃
Only fresh things taste good
# 只有双皮奶不是现做的
Only "Shuang Pi Was" was made in advance
# 然后把姜汁挤出来
Then squeeze out the ginger juice
# 把姜汁挤出来
Squeeze out the ginger juice
# 很浓的姜汁
Thick ginger juice
# 等一下 冻一下水牛奶
Wait and cool down the milk for a bit
# 水牛奶太热不好
Water buffalo milk should not be too hot
# 用的是凉水（为牛奶降温）
We use cold water (to cool down the milk)
# 可以了
Alright
# 现在撞
Now mix it
# 好浓郁的姜汁的味道
Such a strong gingery scent
# 可以了
Alright
# 凝固了
Coagulated
# 对啊 凝固了可以吃了
Yeah, coagulated. Good to eat now
# 是凝固的
It's coagulated
# 我以为是液态的 没想到是凝固的
I thought it's liquid. But it's coagulated
# 你看
Look
# 这个是双皮奶 你那个是姜撞奶
This one is "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk")
That one is "Jiang Zhuang Nai" ("ginger milk")
# 我们看看这是双皮奶
Let's take a look. This is "Shuang Pi Nai"
# 它（姜撞奶）相对来说 还能够晃动
Comparatively, this "Jiang Shuang Nai" can shake a bit
# 但是这个（双皮奶）就像果冻一样
However, this "Shuang Pi Nai" is like a jelly
# 没有那么容易晃动
Not that easy to shake
# 而且双皮奶表面是有褶皱的
And there are wrinkles on the surface of "Shuang Pi Nai"
# 这个的表面看上去就是光滑很多
This one has a much smoother surface
# 这个姜汁撞奶
This is ginger juice and milk
# 吃一口就是浓重的姜的味道
Have a bite, and there's a strong gingery scent in your mouth
# 但这个 双皮奶就是浓重的奶味
On the other hand, "Shuang Pi Nai" is just strong milky flavor
# 双皮奶里面是加了蛋清和糖的
There are egg white and sugar added into "Shuang Pi Nai"
# 所以吃起来会更香
So it tastes even better
# 吃完姜撞奶 你会感觉 浑身发热
After having the "Jiang Zhuang Nai", you may find your whole body heating up
# 走的时候又买了一瓶水牛奶
Before leaving, we bought a bottle of water buffalo milk
# 当地的水牛奶
Local water buffalo milk
# 这个就是我们刚才 从阿姨店里买的水牛奶
This is the water buffalo milk we just bought from the auntie
# 咱们就单独尝一尝
Let's have a try
# 这一个牛奶有什么样不同的地方
and see the difference with regular milk
# 哇 甘甜
Wow, sweet
# 确实香
So flavorful, indeed
# 奶味会比普通咱们喝的这些牌子的牛奶
It has a much stronger milky flavor
# 奶味要重很多
compared to the regular branded milk
# 不过这次买的牛奶 它的保质期很短
However, the buffalo milk didn't stay long
# 第二天早上 它就变酸了
In the next morning, it went sour
# 挑战做双皮奶
Challenge: making "Shuang Pi Nai" ("double skin milk")
# 首先呢 我们要把这个牛奶加热
First, we need to heat up the milk
# 但是不能让它烧开
But don't let it boil
# 加热 但是不要沸腾
Heat, but don't boil
# 我们用筷子挡一下奶皮
We block the milk skin with chopsticks
# 把牛奶倒进去
and pour the milk in
# 这样 碗底就有奶皮了
In this way, there's milk skin at the bottom of the bowl
# 加蛋清 白糖
Add egg white and sugar
# 不要放太多的糖
Not too much sugar
# 使劲地搅拌
Mix it hard
# 如果说 可以的话 过滤一下
And, if possible, strain it
# 原来以为是一个教程
I thought it would be a tutorial
# 没想到 它是一个事故
Didn't expect it ended up an accident
# 好像不太凝固
It doesn't seem quite coagulated
# 一般我们在店里吃的双皮奶都是凉的
Normally, the "Shuang Pi Nai" we have at restaurants is cool
# 顶多它是温的
Or at most warm
# 这个 现在是烫的
It's quite hot at the moment
# 咱们凉一会儿再吃吧
Let's wait for it to cool down
# 还是很烫的
It's still pretty hot
# 来 试一试我的大作
Come one, have a try of my masterpiece
# 不知道它有没有成功
Not sure if it's successful or not
# 反正 样子是有了
Anyway, it looks correct
# 因为我没有加很多糖
As I didn't add a lot of sugar
# 所以它吃起来没有那么甜
it doesn't taste as sweet
# 但是依然有很重的奶香味
Still, there's a very strong milky flavor
# 味道还是不错的
The taste is not bad
# 继续努力
Keep working